<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="bogalake_info">
        \nBoga Lake is the highest natural lake of Bangladesh situated at Bandarban. Boga Lake is around 10 acres in size and situated 1800 feet above the sea level, surrounded by hills. Lake water is so crystal clear that one can see fishes under the beautiful blue colored transparent water. Another wonderful point about this lake is, it changes its colour from time to time.You can enjoy camp fire beside the lake, that will be unbelievable and mind-blowing memory in your life. There is a small Tribal \'Bawm\' village just beside of the lake. One night in this \'Bawm\' village can be a great experience.
\n\nLocation:\n
Boga Mukh Para, Ramu, Bandarban.
\n\nClimate:\n
Winter season is the most preferable time to visit or trekking for Boga Lake. Rainy season is difficult to trekking but if you like adventure then choose rainy season.
\n\nHow to get there:\n
First need to reach at Bandarban from Dhaka by Bus.
\n\n
Then need to start towards \'Koikhong jhiri\', Ruma Ghat by local Bus or \'Chander Gari\'.
\n\n
Cross river \'Sangu\' by engine boat,  will take 30 minutes to reach at Ramu Bazar.
\n\n
At \'Ramu Bazar\' need to hire a guide and must register tourist name, guide name and additional informations to the
military check post. One can stay at night there. \'Ruma Bazar\' to \'Boga Lake\' actually \'Boga Mukh Para\' is about 29 km.
\n\n
From Ramu Bazar one can start journey by trekking through the \'Jhiri Path\', it will take 7/8 hours to reach or can hire
\'Chander Gari\' and will take about 2.5 hours.
\n\n
After starting the journey by \'Chander Gari\' need to register tourist\'s name at police station and this journey to Boga
Lake is not smooth. At the middle of the journey there is a stopes where can make some tea.
\n\n
After reaching the camp, need to walk to \'Boga Lake\' or may manage the \'Chander Gari\' again to reach up to the \'Boga Mukh
Para\' and will take extra 500 BDT.
\n\n
Transport :\n
Dhaka to Bandarban by Bus : 600 BDT and will take 8-10 hours.
Bandarban Town to \'Koikhang Jhiri\' Ruma Ghat by local Bus : 100 BDT per person.
Sangu river cross by engine Boat : 80-100 BDT per person.
Ruma Bazar to Boga Lake (Boga Mukh para) by \'Chander Gari\' : 3500-4000 BDT.
\n\n
Where to stay:\n
Hotels are available in Bandarban town, to stay at night.
At \'Ruma Bazar\' there are some hotels and boarding houses to stay night.
At Boga Lake, \'Boga Mukh Para\' can hire some small cottages as well as can stay at tribal\’s homes as paying guest and
will pay 100-150 BDT per person per night.
Local restaurants are available at \'Ruma bazar\' and  \'Boga Lake\' (Boga Mukh Para).
\n\nAccessories needs to have:\n
Very much careful about mosquitoes and insects. Take extra cloths. Trekkers must have the mentality to walk about 7/8
hours through the hilly roads. Trekkers should carry fresh water, saline, glucose, energy drinks, painkillers, Medicine
etc. Fix how much the guide will cost you. The standard rate is 300-500 BDT per day.
    </string>

</resources>