<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="foyslake_info">
        \nFoy\'s Lake is a man-made lake in Chittagong, Bangladesh. It is a place of enjoyment and refreshment. People come here
to enjoy their holidays with family and friends. An amusement park, managed by the Concord group, is located here.
The park has a water theme park, resort and an amusement center. Here you can enjoy boat rides on the lake, landscaping,
concerts with floating stages, scenic walking trails and many other fun activities. The biggest attraction is the beauty
of the lake and its surrounding hills.
\n\n
Location:\n
Pahartali, Northern part of Chittagong\n\n
Famous for:\n
Lake, Zoo, Amusement Park
\n\n
How to get there:\n
You can go to the Foy’s Lake by Bus,Auto Rickshaw,Tempu or by other private vehicle.It will take about half hour from
the center place of Chittagong city by auto rickshaw.
\n\n
Where to stay:\n
You can stay in Foy’s lake resorts as well as there are many hotels in Chittagong city some of them are the best hotels
of the country.You can also find some reasonable hotels to stay and have food.
\n\n
Entry Permits/Fees:\n
Only Entry fees: BDT 120 ( Adult ).
Only Entry fees: BDT 60 ( Kids ).
Entry + 3 Rides Once + Pepsi / Ice-Cream : BDT 280 (Adult (except Bumper Car and Boat Rides) ).
Entry + 3 Rides Once + pepsi / Ice-Cream : BDT 170 Kid (except Bumper Car and Boat Rides).
Entry + All Rides Once + Pepsi / Ice-Cream : BDT 300 For Adult (except Bumper Car and Boat Rides).
Entry + All Rides Once + Pepsi / Ice-Cream : BDT 220 For Kids (except Bumper Car and Boat Rides).
Entry + All Rides Once + Lunch/Dinner : BDT 500 For All (except Bumper Car and Boat Rides).
Entry + All Rides Once + Lunch/Dinner : BDT 2000 4 Persons Together (except Bumper Car and Boat Rides).
Entry + 3 Rides Once + Lunch/Dinner + SW Entry : BDT 600 For All.
Entry + 3 Rides Once + Lunch/Dinner + SW Entry : BDT 2550 4 Persons Together.
\n\n
Opening time:
10:30 AM\n
Closing time:\n
Weekdays: 6.00 PM
Weekend 7.00 PM
    </string>
</resources>